# **Graeme Thornber**

Mobile: +6421 0292 4529

E-mail Address: gdthornber@gmail.com Website: www.graemethornber.com



## **Profile**

I am a Front-End / UI / pHp Web Developer with almost a decade of industry experience based in Auckland, New Zealand. I specialize in all aspects of building highly functional responsive websites using the latest available technologies.

After completing high school in 1996 I spent several years in hospitality before gaining a Diploma in Web Development from Natcoll (now Youbee) in 2006. I have since worked as a Web Developer in Auckland, Wellington and Bonn, Germany.

My strongest skills are in Front End development using technologies like HTML5, SASS/LESS and jQuery. I also have a solid Back End background with pHp & mySQL, and have more recently picked up skills like AngularJS, Node.js, Firebase and MongoDB.

I stand out amongst other developers due to my social nature, ability to communicate very effectively in English both spoken and written, and stage experience acting, singing and playing guitar. I also have plenty of experience working remotely and am fluent with the latest communication and collaboration software such as Git, Slack, JIRA and Bitbucket.

## **Education**

2005 – 2006 Natcoll (now Youbee) in Auckland, New Zealand

Diploma in Web Development

1992 – 1996 Howick College, Auckland, New Zealand

English, Japanese, Drama, Music, Computer Studies

# **Employment History**

2014 - Present

Freelancer (Auckland, NZ) - www.graemethornber.com

Full Stack Developer for digital agencies in Auckland including:

Colenso BBDO, DDB (RAPP), Image Center Group, iDesignMedia, Insight Creative, J. Walter Thompson, Redfire Design, Satellite Media, Touchcast (Clemenger / BBDO).

#### 2011 - 2013

### Scopevisio AG (Bonn, Germany) - www.scopevisio.com

Senior PHP Developer - Drupal, Wordpress, jQuery, Web Services

#### 2010 - 2011

### +The Church+ (Wellington, NZ) - www.thechurch.co.nz

Lead Developer, Project Manager, Wordpress, jQuery, Google Maps API

#### 2008 - 2010

### Solutionists (Auckland, NZ) - www.solutionists.co.nz

Front End Developer - HTML, CSS, Javascript, Campaign Monitor, ASP.NET

#### 2007 - 2008

#### Freelance Developer (Auckland, NZ)

Drupal, Joomla, Silverstripe for clients such as Zest Media and Brown Paper Baq.

#### 1997 - 2006

#### Various bars & restaurants in Auckland and London

Waiter, Bartender, Restaurant Supervisor, Event Manager

# Technical Skills (ordered by highest skill level):

- HTML5: Bootstrap 3, Foundation, Twig, JADE, Mustache
- CSS3: Responsive LESS, SASS, Stylus, Compass
- Javascript: jQuery, JSON, AngularJS, Google Maps API, Masonry, Isotope
- PHP & MySQL: OOP, MVC, SOAP, REST, cURL, Symfony, Zend
- CMS theme & plugin authoring in Wordpress, Drupal, Bolt, Joomla, Silverstripe
- Email Templates with Litmus, Campaign Monitor, MailChimp, Mandrill API
- Node.js, Express 4, Firebase, MongoDB, Mongoose, Mocha
- Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Fireworks, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Flash
- CLI: Terminal, Putty, Grunt, Gulp, Node, Bower, Homebrew
- Admin / Team Tools: Git, Slack, JIRA, Bitbucket, Beanstalk, Basecamp
- E-Commerce setup and management with Magento, Shopify, WooCommerce
- CDNs / Cloud Services / Social Media: AWS, Rackspace, YouTube, Facebook
- Apache / Nginx server administration: MAMP, PHPmyadmin, Plesk, cPanel
- IDEs: Sublime Text, Atom, Notepad++, NetBeans, Visual Studio, Eclipse
- Website analysis / management: Google Webmaster Tools and Analytics
- XML/HTML parsing/processing, PDF creation with PHP and FPDF
- Basic knowledge of Xcode, Swift, Linux, C, ASP.NET and Flash Actionscript

## Other skills:

- Excellent command of English, both spoken and written (formal & creative)
- Typing speed of over 80 words per minute
- Can speak German and basic Japanese
- Over 20 years experience playing guitar and other instruments
- Wit, personality and an appropriate sense of humour

# Skills I plan to acquire:

- iOS / Android app development, Xcode, Swift, Cocoa Touch
- Exposure to more Javascript Frameworks: Backbone, Ember, Dojo
- More experience with open source MVC frameworks
- Extra programming fluency: Ruby/Rails, Java, C/C++, Perl, Python, C#

### The most recent sites I built were:

www.stoptober.nz www.mc.co.nz

## Examples of my work can be found on my website at:

www.graemethornber.com